export const chapter = "Chapter - 16: Rise of Nationalism (1885-1919) ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the main event described in the text?",
        optionA: "The First World War",
        optionB: "The Partition of Bengal",
        optionC: "The Revolt of 1857",
        correctAnswer: "The Revolt of 1857",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which phase of Indian nationalism focused on using constitutional agitation for demanding reforms?",
        optionA: "Moderate Phase",
        optionB: "Radical Phase",
        optionC: "Gandhian Phase",
        correctAnswer: "Moderate Phase",
      },
      {
        question: "Who founded the Indian National Congress?",
        optionA: "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        optionB: "A.O. Hume",
        optionC: "Dadabhai Naoroji",
        correctAnswer: "A.O. Hume",
      },
      {
        question: "What was the main reason behind the Partition of Bengal?",
        optionA: "Administrative reasons",
        optionB: "Religious considerations",
        optionC: "Political motives",
        correctAnswer: "Political motives",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which movement encouraged people to use only Indian goods and boycott British-manufactured goods?",
        optionA: "The Swadeshi and Boycott Movements",
        optionB: "The Radical Movement",
        optionC: "The Revolutionaries Movement",
        correctAnswer: "The Swadeshi and Boycott Movements",
      },
      {
        question: "Who were the leaders of the Revolutionary Movement?",
        optionA: "Mahatma Gandhi and Jawaharlal Nehru",
        optionB: "Ajit Singh and Ashwini Kumar Dutt",
        optionC: "Raja Ram Mohan Roy and Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar",
        correctAnswer: "Ajit Singh and Ashwini Kumar Dutt",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which organization aimed to strike terror in the British and targeted unpopular British officers?",
        optionA: "Indian National Congress",
        optionB: "Ghadar Party",
        optionC: "The Swadeshi Movement",
        correctAnswer: "Ghadar Party",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What impact did the First World War have on India's struggle for freedom?",
        optionA: "It led to immediate independence.",
        optionB: "It resulted in stricter laws and harsh enforcement.",
        optionC: "It united Indians and the British for a common cause.",
        correctAnswer: "It resulted in stricter laws and harsh enforcement.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is credited with devising the methods of Ahimsa (non-violence) and Satyagraha (insistence on truth) to attain independence?",
        optionA: "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
        optionB: "Subramania Iyer",
        optionC: "Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi",
        correctAnswer: "Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi",
      },
      {
        question: "What was the primary aim of the Indian National Congress?",
        optionA: "To achieve immediate independence through violent means",
        optionB: "To demand constitutional reforms from the British government",
        optionC: "To promote religious harmony among Indians",
        correctAnswer:
          "To demand constitutional reforms from the British government",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The greatest and the most widespread armed uprising which shook the foundations of the British rule in India was the __________.",
        options: [
          "Revolt of 1857",
          "Indian National Congress",
          "Partition of Bengal",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Revolt of 1857",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Indian soldiers of Britain's army in India and the vast masses of peasants, artisans, and others who had been ruined by British economic policies were united by the common aim of overthrowing British __________.",
        options: ["administration", "rule", "dominance"],
        correctAnswer: "rule",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The growth of Indian nationalism started in the __________ century.",
        options: ["seventeenth", "eighteenth", "nineteenth"],
        correctAnswer: "nineteenth",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Some newspapers published during this period played an important role in the rise of __________.",
        options: [
          "British dominance",
          "Indian nationalism",
          "religious movements",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Indian nationalism",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Many associations or organizations were found to reform society and promote __________.",
        options: ["industrialization", "agriculture", "education"],
        correctAnswer: "education",
      },
      {
        question:
          "From about the mid-nineteenth century, some national associations were formed which demanded a share in the British government and some rights for the Indians. A need was felt for an all India organization, and the Indian National Association was founded by __________.",
        options: [
          "Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi",
          "A.O. Hume",
          "Surendranath Banerjee",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Surendranath Banerjee",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The birth of Indian National Congress in 1885 gave a final spark to the growth of national consciousness among the Indians. A.O. Hume, a retired civil servant, was credited with its __________.",
        options: ["success", "formation", "leadership"],
        correctAnswer: "formation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Indian Nationalism was broadly divided into three phases: __________.",
        options: [
          "Colonial, Monarchist, and Republican",
          "Moderate, Radical, and Gandhian",
          "Conservative, Liberal, and Socialist",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Moderate, Radical, and Gandhian",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Gandhian Phase was led by Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi. He devised the methods of __________ to attain independence.",
        options: [
          "violence and aggression",
          "Ahimsa (non-violence) and Satyagraha (insistence on truth)",
          "economic reforms and industrialization",
        ],
        correctAnswer:
          "Ahimsa (non-violence) and Satyagraha (insistence on truth)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The decision of the Partition of Bengal was announced in July 1905 by the Viceroy of India, Lord Curzon. The partition took effect in October 1905 and separated the largely Muslim eastern areas from the largely Hindu western areas. The real reason behind the partition was administrative and not __________.",
        options: ["geographical", "administrative", "religious"],
        correctAnswer: "administrative",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Punjab is a state in the Northern Plains.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Haryana is known as the 'Milk Pail of India.'",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Uttar Pradesh leads the country in the production of tea.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Delhi is often called 'Mini India' because people from all over India live there.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Bihar is known for its rich mineral deposits.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Jharkhand is rich in mineral deposits of gold.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "West Bengal lies entirely in the Northern Plains.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Assam is drained by the river Brahmaputra.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Tripura is surrounded by Myanmar on three sides.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The major festivals celebrated in Punjab include Christmas.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
